John Berry Jr.

BROOKLYN, NY

Phone: 718 637 1308 | Email: JOHNWBERRYJR@gmail.com

Summary -

Creative and tech-savvy Human Resources professional with over 10 years of progressive experience across a broad range of people operations and varied department segments within government.

Proven ability to combine vision, ingenuity, strong work ethic and leadership qualities to support smooth operations and improve outdated systems for optimal workflow.

Education -

Kingsborough College – Associates in Graphic Design Inducted in the Phi Theta Kappa honors society.

Graduated 2014

Experience -

Department of Sanitation

Health Benefits Coordinator, Human Resources

2019 - Present

- Oversee and assist in the processing of Health Benefits Applications.
- Perform various Human Resource and Health Benefits related functions within NYCAPS, including constant monitoring and auditing of employee records.
- Assists managers with administrative tasks, scheduling, ordering, and inventory responsibilities.
- Assisted with the production of two web applications to implement in the day to day tasks for Human Resources.
- Managed Family Medical Leave Act (FMLA) approval process for eligibility.
- Compile reports related to FMLA, Workers Compensation and health benefits and various leave without pay.
- Panelist for New Hire Orientation sessions.
- Supervise recruitment staff in the absence of the unit supervisor.

Community Associate, Human Resources

2017 - 2019

- Communicated effectively with the public and DSNY employees regarding issues concerning employee services
- Complete understanding of Office of Labor Relations (OLR) and DSNY Health Benefits policies.
- Re/created and updated agency forms for digital use.
- Compile reports related to new hires, FMLA, Workers Compensation and health benefits.
- Lead the processing of new hires.
- Monitored screening interviews for open requisitions

Clerical Associate, Operations

2015 - 2017

- Built & designed Microsoft Access program databases, changing from paper to digital document input and storage.
- Maintained enough fuel for DSNY vehicles and equipment through fuel analysis and used data to manage order distributions with various vendors.
- Liaised between various contracted vendors and the Department of Sanitation to complete necessary work orders and keep operations running smoothly.
- Monitored all DSNY radio channels for incidents that require upper DSNY managements' knowledge and help prepare field reports.

John Berry Jr.

BROOKLYN, NY

Phone: 718 637 1308 | Email: JOHNWBERRYJR@gmail.com

College Aide, Human Resources

2008 - 2015

- Lead / Trained new College Aide's and Interns working in Human Resources employee services.
- Communicated with the public and DSNY employees to solve any questions or problems regarding employee services.
- Prepared folders to be distributed to DCAS for all newly hired employees as well as those with title changes.

References -

Debra Davis

Employee Services Unit Supervisor, DSNY

Phone: 646 885 0922 | Email: ddavis@dsny.nyc.gov

Gwendolyn Williams

Supervisor of Operations, DSNY

Phone: 646 885 4842 | Email: gwilliam@dsny.nyc.gov